neo4j.org 2018-09-04

# Privacy Policy - Neo4j Graph Database Platform

Thank you for visiting this Internet web site at neo4j.com, neo4j.org, neo4j.io, graphconnect.com, graphdatabases.com, and opencypher.org(and subdomains thereof) (each a “Site”) offered by Neo4j, Inc., Neo4j Sweden AB , and Neo4j UK Limited (collectively “Neo4j”). Neo4j Sweden AB and Neo4j UK Limited are personal data controllers for the processing of your personal data, under European data protection legislation.  

Our Data Protection Officer can be reached at: [dponeo4j@neo4j.com](mailto:dponeo4j@neo4j.com)

In this privacy policy, the term “personal data” has the meaning as defined in applicable European Data Protection legislation. 

This Privacy Policy describes our policies for Neo4j’s collection, use and disclosure of personal data about users of our Site, users of the services on this Site and users of Neo4j software and services (the "Products"). 

**Information Collection and Use**

You can generally visit our Site(s) without revealing any personal data about yourself. However, to use some of the services and functionality of the Site and Products, such as to use Neo4j Desktop or download white papers, you may be required to register for an account or fill out a form to provide us with certain personal data that can be used to contact or identify you. Personal data may include, but is not limited to your name. 

We use your personal data to:

  * _Communicate with You and Tell You About Neo4j Products_ _  
_ When you register for an account or otherwise contact us with questions or comments or submit a proposed talk, we will collect personal data such as your name, e-mail address, company name, job title and/or function and any other contact or personal data that you voluntarily transmit with your communications to us. We also may collect personal data about you that you elect to upload to the Site when you use our Site and services.  

  * _Provide and to Facilitate the Delivery of Neo4j Products that You Request_  
When you download our software products we may collect information about the usage of our Products, such as, product edition, version downloaded, system type and IP address and database instance identifier. 

  * _Respond to your Comments or Questions or Provide information Requested by You_  
We offer online communities and messaging through our website services and other platforms where users can share their experiences.  When you choose to participate in these communications, we collect personal data and business information.

  * _Use our Support Services_   
For customer support, you will be required to register for an account with your name, email address, company name, username and password. If you use our Products we will collect the information that you voluntarily include in your saved queries, including, personal data and business information.

  * _Better understand how the Site is used  
_We collect information about the use of the Site that is maintained, used and disclosed. This information includes IP addresses (which is personal data under European data protection laws) and other information about the Site visitors’ equipment to analyze for trends and statistics in the aggregate. We use such aggregate information to administer and improve the Site, track users’ movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.

Neo4j processes the personal data for the following purposes, based on the following legal grounds:

**Purpose of the processing** | 

**Legal basis for the processing**  
  
---|---  
  
Communicate with you and tell you about Neo4j Products 

| 

Pursue legitimate interests  
  
Provide and facilitate the delivery of Neo4j Products that you request

| 

Fulfil contractual obligations, or if you represent a legal entity, to pursue our legitimate interests  
  
Respond to your comments or questions or provide information requested by you 

| 

Fulfil contractual obligations  
  
Improve the content and general administration of the Site and our services

| 

Pursue legitimate interests  
  
Provide our support services

| 

Fulfil contractual obligations  
  
Better understand how the Site is used

| 

Pursue legitimate interests  
  
Neo4j’s legitimate interests are: (a) providing Products and other services to business customers; (b) sending marketing communications; and (c) improving and administrating the Site, and improving the content of the Site.

If you elect to post a comment otherwise make personal data publicly available on our Site, such as in a comment to one of our blogs, other users of the Site will be able to view such comment and/or your personal data. 

**Choice**

You have the ability to “opt-out” or unsubscribe from continuing to receive any Neo4j marketing communications via email at [dponeo4j@neo4j.com](mailto:dponeo4j@neo4j.com) at any time. Neo4j also provides opt-out information in all marketing communications via an “unsubscribe” link in communication emails, which directly unsubscribes you from any further communication from Neo4j.

**Children’s Privacy**

Neo4j recognizes the privacy interests of children and we encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children’s online activities and interests. This Site is not intended for children under the age of 16. Neo4j does not target its services or this Site to children under 16. Neo4j does not knowingly collect personal data from children under the age of 16.

**Cookies and Tracking Data**

We may use small text files called cookies and other tracking mechanisms to improve overall Site experience. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies on our Site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. To learn more about the cookies and other tracking mechanisms that we use, please see our <http://neo4j.com/privacy-policy/cookies/>.

**Disclosure**

We may provide your personal data and the data generated by cookies and the aggregate information to the vendors and service agencies that we may engage to assist us in providing our services to you for their use solely to provide us with such assistance. For example, we may use a third party payment processor to process your payments. In connection with the processing of such payments, we do not retain any personal data or any financial information such as credit card numbers. Rather, all such information is provided directly to our third party processors. Unless we give you the choice to opt-out and you do not exercise your opt-out right, Neo4j’s service providers do not have any right to use personal data we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us or for a purpose incompatible with the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by you. We will not disclose your sensitive or other personal data to a third party unless you have provided us with affirmative or explicit (opt in) consent. If you use our Neo4j Browser Sync service, we use Auth0 to authenticate you and any information that you save in our Neo4j Browser Sync service will be hosted by our service provider Firebase. Firebase’s use of your information is subject to Firebase’s policies at <https://www.firebase.com/terms/privacy-policy.html> .

We will also disclose your personal data (a) if we are required to do so by law, regulation or other government authority or otherwise in cooperation with an ongoing investigation of a governmental authority, (b) to enforce the Neo4j Terms of Use agreement or to protect our rights or (c) to protect the safety of users of our Site and our services. We will not sell your personal data to any company or organization, but we may transfer your personal data to a successor entity upon a merger, consolidation or other corporate reorganization in which Neo4j participates or to a purchaser or acquirer of all or substantially all of Neo4j’s assets to which this Site relates.

**Links to Third Party Sites**

The Site may provide links to other Web sites or resources over which Neo4j does not have control (“External Web Sites”).  For example, our pages at Slack, Google Groups, and Stackoverflow are External Web Sites. Such links do not constitute an endorsement by Neo4j of those External Web Sites. You acknowledge that Neo4j is providing these links to you only as a convenience, and further agree that Neo4j is not responsible for the content of such External Web Sites. Your use of External Web Sites is subject to the terms of use and privacy policies located on the linked to External Web Sites.

**Social Plugins on Our Site**

We may use social plugins on our Site and may include icons that allow you to interact with third party social networks such as LinkedIn, Twitter and Facebook.  For example, you may “like” us or a book on Facebook or follow us or Tweet about us on Twitter. If you use our Neo4j Browser Sync, Neo4j Cloud and Neo4j Sandbox services, you will be required to login using your GitHub, Twitter and/or Google credentials. The third party social plugin may set a cookie when your browser creates a connection to the servers of such social networks and the plugin may transmit your data to the social networks. 

Additionally, there may be places where we offer the ability for Neo4j applications to connect with third party social networks, such as Twitter or Facebook.  We will collect certain data that the third party social networks provide to us and we will only use that data to provide the application for your use. Your use of these social plugins is subject to the privacy policies of the third party social networks.

**Retaining your personal data**

We keep your personal data for as long as we need it for the purposes for which it was collected. Where we keep your data for purposes beyond those of our contractual fulfilment, we keep the data only as long as necessary and/or mandated by law for the respective purpose.

When we decide how long we will keep your information we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure, why we need it, and any relevant legal requirements.

We may anonymize your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes, in which case we may use this information indefinitely.

**Security**

We may employ procedural and technological measures, consistent with industry practice. Such measures are reasonably designed to help protect your personal data from loss, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. Neo4j may use secure socket layer and other security measures to help prevent unauthorized access to your personal data. The security of the Neo4j Browser Sync service is provided by our cloud hosting provider, Firebase and you can read more about Firebase’s security policies at <https://www.firebase.com/terms/privacy-policy.html>.

**Your Rights Regarding Personal Data Concerning You**

You have a right to receive confirmation whether personal data concerning the person in question is being processed by us, to receive information about the processing and to access the personal data, and to obtain a copy of the personal data; object to our processing of personal data; have personal data concerning you deleted, and to have incorrect data about you corrected, and to restrict the processing of data concerning you; data portability, meaning that you in certain cases have a right to receive personal data concerning you in a commonly used format, or to have it transmitted to another personal data controller in accordance with your specification; and to not be subject to a decision based only on automatic processing.   

Please note that the exercise of these rights is not absolute, and that for some rights certain criteria must be at hand for the right to exercised, or that certain exceptions might be applicable.

Neo4j provides you with the ability to review and update the registration information that you provide to us by contacting us at [dponeo4j@neo4j.com](mailto:dponeo4j@neo4j.com).

**Questions**

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy please contact us via email at [dponeo4j@neo4j.com](mailto:dponeo4j@neo4j.com). 

**Notice to Users Outside of the United States of America (Transfers)**

Any information you enter on this Site may be transferred outside of the country in which you are located, to the United States of America, which does not offer an equivalent level of protection to that required in other countries, such as the European Union. In particular, you are advised that the United States of America uses a sectoral model of privacy protection that relies on a mix of legislation, governmental regulation, and self-regulation. The European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) allows for transfer of personal data from the European Union to a third country in certain situations. By agreeing to the terms of use and this Privacy Policy, you agree and consent to the transfer of all such information to the United States of America which may not offer an equivalent level of protection to that required in other countries, particularly the European Union, and to the processing of that information by Neo4j on servers located in the United States of America as described in this Privacy Policy.

Additionally, transfers of personal data from the European Union to the United States of America are made using the EU Commission’s Standard Contractual Clauses (Decision 2004/915/EC) in accordance with applicable law. Please contact us for more information about this, or if you want to obtain a copy of the Standard Contractual Clauses used.

**Complaint**

If you have any complaints regarding our processing of your personal data, you may file a complaint to the competent data protection authority. You can find out more about the local data protection authorities under the following link http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm.

**Privacy Policy Updates**

Due to the Internet’s rapidly evolving nature, Neo4j may need to update this Privacy Policy from time to time. If so, Neo4j will post our updated Privacy Policy on our Site along with notice that the Privacy Policy has been changed so you are always aware of what personal data we may collect and how we may use this information. Neo4j may also send registered users of the Site e-mail notifications notifying such users of any material changes to the Privacy Policy. Neo4j encourages you to review this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes. Your continued use of this Site and/or continued provision of personal data to us will be subject to the terms of the then-current Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy was last updated: July 20, 2018 

**Contact Information to European Companies**

Neo4j Sweden AB: Nordenskiöldsgatan 24, 211 19 Malmö, Sweden

Neo4j UK Limited: Friars Bridge Court, 41-45 Blackfriars Road, London SE1 8NZ, United Kingdom
